## **ALLAN P. FLORES**

## 10201 Lindley Ave, Northridge, CA, USA

allanpflores@yahoo.com: Cel Phone: +18125506911

Extensive Supply Chain Management experience in various roles, both globally and locally. As part of these experiences, I have helped various organizations by developing leading edge processes for supply chain, manufacturing and logistics, particularly in the areas of Integrated Business Planning — Oliver Wight Model (IBP) or Sales and Operations Planning (S&OP), demand planning and management, distribution and warehousing operations, transportation management, cold chain management, purchasing, and customer service. I have led implementation of several ERP systems like SAP and BPCS.

#### **EDUCATION:**

Master in Applied Data Science from Syracuse University, USA (currently enrolled, GPA to date = 3.97 out of 4.0)

- Graduating in May 2020

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering from Saint Louis University, Philippines (Cum Laude)

#### **CERTIFICATION:**

Certified Supply Chain Professional (CSCP) - APICS

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES:**

MONDE NISSIN CORPORATION (On sabbatical/study leave ending in June 2020) Supply Chain Management Director, Philippines

10/2016 - 10/2018

- Responsible in leading the supply chain of at least \$1B food manufacturing company. Led the Demand and Supply Planning, Procurement, Distribution and Warehousing Operations, Customer Service, and Supply Chain Control and Development departments of the company covering 11 distribution centers nationwide with ambient and cold chain products.
- Responsible in implementing the Integrated Business Planning (IBP) or Sales and Operations Planning (S&OP),
  establishing and achieving the Supply Chain KPI's and targets, implementing procurement spend analytics and
  statistical forecasting tool, executing the Distribution Center Network strategies, institutionalizing SKU
  rationalization process, leading the initiative of improving manufacturing scheduling adherence and other key
  processes that can drive operational efficiencies looking at both internal and external supply chain.
- Led the selection and management of all distribution center third party service providers (e.g. DHL, Li & Fung). This included strategies, costings, performance appraisal and process improvement.
- Implemented the process of establishing target inventory levels across all warehouses that significantly reduced inventories. Key driver in helping the whole organization understand and embrace the value of supply chain especially in an environment with growing complexity. Responsible in optimizing the use of system (SAP) and reporting tools to facilitate in supply chain analytics. Introduced a new department, Supply Chain Control and Development, which covered training and development of all supply chain management staff that extends to our supply chain partners or third-party service providers. Responsible in leading 200 full time permanent employees and third-party service providers.

# MEAD JOHNSON NUTRITION Global Process Head for Planning, Indiana, USA

08/2013 - 09/2016

Responsible for the end-to-end demand and supply planning processes and material master data across functional silos and geographic boundaries. Led and facilitated the regional business process communities (Regions North America, Latin America, Europe, and Asia) to ensure that needs of the business was identified, evaluated, prioritized within the process community, with appropriate key stakeholder approval. Ensured that the business requirements were translated to Information Technology (using SAP and other tools).

- Maintained a strategic planning road map to deliver process improvements (in the areas of Forecasting, DRP, MPS, Detailed Production Scheduling, MRP, Inventory Management) that contributed to the growth and profitability of the company. Among process improvement initiatives were Sales and Operations Planning (S&OP)/ Integrated Business Planning (IBP) process, statistical forecasting, long term planning, VMI, Constraint Capacity Planning, SKU rationalization, and JIT among other things. In charge of the training and development strategies in building a community of users and subject matter experts.
- Ensured sharing of best practices in the regional and global organization. Led process audit in all the markets
  across the globe and ensured that all improvements and action plans took place. Was successful of bringing
  about gains in process efficiency and effectiveness adding enterprise-wide value.

# MEAD JOHNSON NUTRITION **Demand and Supply Planning Manager, Canada**

09/2011 - 07/2013

- Responsible in finalizing product demand to the SKU, brand and company level in collaboration with sales, marketing, supply chain, and finance. Implemented the S&OP, demand planning and SKU rationalization processes. Established methodology in calculating target inventory levels. Responsible in establishing the demand and supply planning KPIs, and ensured that set targets are met and challenged.
- Responsible in recommending process improvements in North America's demand and supply planning processes in reducing supply chain lead-time, reducing cost of inventory and improving customer service level.

#### SAPUTO FOODS DAIRY

## **Demand Planning and Supply Chain Optimization Manager, Canada**

04/2008 - 08/2011

- Led the national demand and supply planning of key fluid products (total Canada market) and local requirements
  of the Western Region (British Columbia and Alberta). Led supply chain optimization projects like DRP
  implementation, sales forecasting process and cross-docking operations. Responsible in leading the short to longterm manufacturing capacity plans. Led the coordination with third-party contract manufacturers based in the US.
- Led a team of four demand planners. Key achievements included implementation of the Sales and Operations Planning process (S&OP), integration of supply chain activities for the newly acquired dairy company, recommended the most efficient means of shipping products across Canada by identifying distribution lanes with lower transportation and warehousing costs, and turned around KPIs to above targets.

## **SANOFI-AVENTIS**

## Sales Forecasting Dep't. Head, Canada

04/2005 - 03/2008

- As Sales Forecasting Dep't. Head of Canada. Led the forecasting / demand planning of all products of the company covering 3 business units (oncology, bone and metabolism, cardio-vascular). Responsible in providing inputs to finalize sales force targets by province.
- Key achievements included implemented the sales forecasting tool, achieved forecast accuracy of 95% making Canada as No. 1 country in the Region Europe and Canada in terms of sales forecasting process, started and established the Sales Forecasting department as the first mandate using Supply Chain and Sales experience and implemented Sales and Marketing KPIs and Brand Scorecards.

# SANOFI-AVENTIS Sales Director, Philippines

04/2003 - 03/2005

- As Sales Director of Aventis Philippines. Led the company's sales division covering Cardiovascular, Diabetes
  and Bone. Directed sales and business development functions including new product rollouts, segmentation and
  targeting, key account management and contract negotiation. Held budget and P&L responsibilities.
- Provided cross-functional team training, coaching and mentoring. Designed and implemented sales plans and programs in achieving market leadership and gaining market share. Led product portfolio and sales configuration committees in the Sanofi-Aventis merger.

#### SANOFI-AVENTIS

### **Supply Chain and Commercial Effectiveness Director, Philippines**

04/2002 - 12/2002

- As Supply Chain and Commercial Effectiveness Director of Aventis Philippines. Responsible in leading all functions of supply chain management (Demand and Supply Planning, Purchasing, Import/Export, Distribution, Warehousing) with the addition of commercial effectiveness.
- Commercial effectiveness covered sales territory and target setting, segmentation and targeting and promotional sample effectiveness. Led the redesigning and documentation of core business processes in supply chain. Led negotiations with third-party distributor and contract manufacturers. Member of the company's Executive Committee.

### JAMES HARDIE, INC.

## **Logistics Division Vice President**

05/2001 - 03/2002

 As member of the Executive Committee, led the logistics division and strategic direction of the Demand and Supply Planning, Purchasing, Import/Export, Distribution, Warehousing, and Transportation departments. Mandated significant reduction in distribution and purchasing cost with increased customer service level. Introduced Supply Chain Management in the organization, implemented KPIs and led the development of training programs for all logistics functions including third party service providers. Led 5 managers and 23 employees under the division.

#### **NESTLE**

## **Supply Chain Management Asst. Vice President, Philippines**

06/1996 - 04/2001

- Led the Distribution Center and Warehouse Operations department of the whole company with 28 strategically located distribution centers nationwide. Led in collaborating and negotiating with third-party logistics service providers. Directed all distribution center managers ensuring that policies and standards are in place and implemented. Responsible in continuously evaluating the distribution strategy of the company.
- Represented Supply Chain Management Philippines in the Regionalization Project for Asia and Oceania, that
  involved re-structuring of factories and distribution centers within the Zone Asia/Oceania. Led the implementation
  of all Supply Chain Management activities ensuring readiness of Philippine operations and other affiliates
  (countries within the Zone).
- Led the conceptualization, design and construction of the largest distribution centers based on World-Class warehousing. Implemented the integrated computerized planning system using BPCS (Business Planning and Control System) and Warehouse Management System (WMS). Responsible in designing the supply chain training needs of the supply chain team including third party service providers and key accounts.
- Member of a group composed of selected key personnel across the globe whose task is to improve processes of Marketing, Sales and Supply Chain.

SANDOZ (now NOVARTIS)

Distribution and Warehouse Manager, Philippines Production Planning and Inventory Control Officer, Philippines 1994-1995

1990-1993